Mss.B.R743 Mss.B.R743
American Philosophical Society
Joseph T. Rothrock letters, 1878-1884, to Eli K. Price
Mss.B.R743
American Philosophical Society
9.0 items.
This correspondence relates to botanizing expeditions in the Chesapeake Bay and Virginia, and the University of Pennsylvania and the American Philosophical Society.
9 items.
Rothrock, Joseph T., 1839-1922
Box 1
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Purchased from Hamilton and accessioned, 1957 (1957 689ms).
Biographical/Historical note
Joseph T. Rothrock was a physician, botanist, and forester; he was elected to the American Philosophical Society in 1877.
American Philosophical Society.; Price, Eli K., (Eli Kirk), 1797-1884; University of Pennsylvania.; Botany -- Chesapeake Bay (Md. and Va.); Botany -- Virginia.
- Papers
  - Letters to Mr. [Eli kirk ?] Price, 1878-1884; Rothrock, Joseph T., 1839-1922
    Scope and Contents note
    A.L.S'S 9 pieces Contents: 1878. Sept. 3 1844. Jan. 4 1881. June 8 April 11 1882. Jan. 17 April 20 1883. March 13 July 13 June 24 To be anal.
  - Letter to [Eli Kirk?] Price, Sept. 3, 1878; 10x7-3/4; Rothrock, Joseph T., 1839-1922
    West Chester, A.L.S. 1p.and end. (see Rothrock papers.) Cites Gray and Shaler on conversion of oak areas into praries. Refers to Michaux
  - Letter to [Eli Kirk?] Price, June 8, 1881; 6-3/4x8; Rothrock, Joseph T., 1839-1922
    West Chester, A.L.S. 1p.and end. (see Rothrock papers.) Thanks for notification of his election "to fill the new chair."
  - Letter to [Eli Kirk?] Price, Jan. 17, 1882; 10x7-3/4; Rothrock, Joseph T., 1839-1922
    A.L.S. 1p.and end. (see Rothrock papers.) Authorized Redfield to receive asters and lolidagoes. Refers to Asa Gray.
  - Letter to [Eli Kirk?] Price, March 13, 1883; 9-3/4x8; Rothrock, Joseph T., 1839-1922
    West Chester, A.L.S. 1p.and end. (see Rothrock papers.) Thanks for catalpa seeds and lists his distribution of them.
  - Letter to [Eli Kirk?] Price, June 24, 1883; 10x7-3/4; Rothrock, Joseph T., 1839-1922
    James River, Va., A.L.S. 4p.,end. (see Rothrock papers.) His trip to Virginia. Collecting fossil shells and photographs of geological formations.
  - Letter to [Eli Kirk?] Price, Jan. 4, 1884; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Rothrock, Joseph T., 1839-1922
    West Chester, A.L.S. 1p.and end. (see Rothrock papers.) Thanks for the money. Refers to a paper which he read before the APS.
  - Letter to [Eli kirk?] Price, April 11, 1884; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Rothrock, Joseph T., 1839-1922
    West Chester, A.L.S. 2p.,end. (see Rothrock papers.) His health. Will meet at Dr. Jayne's to discuss biological projects. University of Pennsylvania affairs.
  - Letter to [Eli Kirk?] Price, April 20, 1884; 6-1/4x7-1/2; Rothrock, Joseph T., 1839-1922
    West Chester, A.L.S. 1p.,end. (see Rothrock papers.) Forwards article.
  - Letter to [Eli kirk?] Price, July 13, 1884; 8x5; Rothrock, Joseph T., 1839-1922
    A.L.S. 4p.,end. (see Rothrock papers.) Is photographing Virginia along the James River. His itenerary.